Pierce, Edward Lillie, 1829-1897, recipient. Edward Lillie Pierce letters from various correspondents, 1854-1897 (MS Am 1.65): Guide.
Edward Lillie Pierce letters from various correspondents,
1854-1897.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1.65
Pierce, Edward Lillie, 1829-1897, recipient.
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Letters to Massachusetts lawyer Edward Lillie Pierce from Charles Francis Adams, Samuel Portland Chase, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Carl Schurz, and many other correspondents.
Gift of the family of Edward Lillie Pierce; received: 1918.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Pierce, a lawyer, held many civil offices in Massachusetts, was active in Republican politics, and was the official biographer and executor of Charles Sumner.
Arranged alphabetically by author.
Includes letters to Pierce from Charles Francis Adams, Salmon Portland Chase, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, and Carl Schurz, among many others. Items with an asterisk also include a typed transcription.
- Adams, Charles F. TLS to: Edward L. Pierce., (1)
  - 1896 May 8. Boston., 1 p.
  - 1896 May 11. Boston., 2 pp.
  - 1896 May 13. Boston., 2 pp.
  - 1896 Nov.4. Boston., 2 pp (ALS).
  - 1896 Dec.17. So. Lincoln., 4 pp (ALS).
- Andrew, John A. ALS to: Henry L. Pierce., (2)
  - 1861 Jan.15. Boston., 2 pp*.
  - 1861 Feb.11. Boston., 1 p*.
  - 1861 Mar.23. Boston. 1 p* (A.n.s.).
  - 1861 Apr.1. Boston., 1 p*.
  - 1861 Apr. 5. np. (A.n.s.)., 1 p*.
  - 1861 May 8. Boston., 1 p*.
  - 1861 Jun. 4. Boston., 4 pp*.
  - 1861 Jul. 9. Boston., 5 pp*.
  - 1862 Jan. 23. Boston., 2 pp*.
  - 1862 Aug.16. Boston., 1 p*.
  - 1864 Aug.15. Boston., 2 pp*.
  - 1866 May 24. Boston., 2 pp*.
- Andrew, John A. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (3)
  - 1860 Sep.5. Boston. 1 p (LS).
  - 1861 Jan.12. Boston., 1 p.
  - 1861 Feb.6. Boston., 1 p.
  - 1861 Jun.19. Boston., 2 pp.
  - 1862 Sep.17. Boston., 3 pp.
- Angell, James B. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Jun.3. Ann Arbor., (4); 4 pp.
- Bass, Lewis. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Aug.12. Quincy., (5); 2 pp.
- Bigelow, John. ALS to: [Edward L.] Pierce., (6)
  - nd. Highland Falls on the Hudson., 2 pp.
  - 1896. Jan.13., 3 pp.
- Boutwell, George S. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Jun.1. Boston., (7); 2 pp.
- Brainerd, Cephas. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (8)
  - 1895 Jan.25. New York., 2 pp.
  - 1896 May 26. New York. 2 pp (TLS).
- Bright, John. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (9)
  - 1884 Aug.15. Rochdale., 2 pp.
  - 1884 Aug. 25. Rochdale., 2 pp.
  - 1885 Jan. 5. Rochdale., 8 pp.
  - 1886 Jan.17. Rochdale., 8 pp.
  - 1887 Apr.1. London., 1 p.
  - 1887 Apr.7. Rochdale., 3 pp.
  - 1887 May 13. Rochdale., 1 p.
  - 1879 Jul.3. House of Commons., 1 p.
  - 1881 Aug.29. Rochdale., 1 p.
  - 1881 Sep.2. Rochdale., 1 p.
  - 1881 Oct.28. Rochdale., 4 pp.
  - 1882 May 2. London., 2 pp.
  - 1882 May 27. Rochdale., 2 pp.
  - 1883 Jan.10. Rochdale., 6 pp.
  - 1884 Jun.27. London., 3 pp.
- Bright, John A. (Jr.). ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (10)
  - 1895 Nov.20. Rochdale., 4 pp.
- Brinton, B. H. ALS to: Henry L. Pierce. 1877 Dec.6. Louisville, Ky., (11); 2 pp.
- Brown, Martha. ALS to: E. L. Pierce. 1875 May 15. New Brunswick?, (12); 4 pp.
- Bryce, James. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1897 Mar.22. London., (13); 3 pp.
- Carstensen, A. Riis. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1894 Aug.28. Hornby, Denmark., (14); 3 pp.
  Enclosure in Danish.
- Chamberlain, Daniel H. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Feb.17. New York., (15); 2 pp (TLS).
- Chamberlain, Mellen. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Jul.27. Chelsea., (16); 3 pp.
- Chase, Salmon Portland. MS: "Notes on Critical notice of Greeley's American Conflict ---", (17); 8 pp*.
  Found in papers of E. L. Pierce.
- Chase, Salmon Portland. Signature on official document appointing E.L.Pierce a commissioner for the State of Ohio. 1857 Apr.6., (18a); 1 p.
- Chase, Salmon Portland. ALS (COPY) to: Andrew Jackson. 1865 May 12. Charleston, S.C., (18b); 7 pp.
- Chase, Salmon Portland (1808-1872). ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (18c)
  - 1854 Apr.13. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1854 Sep.1. Concord., 1 p.
  - 1854 Sep.20. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1854 Oct.10. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1854 Nov.28. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1854 Dec.8. Worcester., 1 p.
  - 1855 May 14. New York., 4 pp.
  - 1855 Jun.20. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1855 Oct.20. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1855 Oct.27. Cincinnati., 2 pp.
  - 1855 Nov.13. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1856 Apr.15. Columbus, Ohio., 4 pp.
  - 1856 May 19. Columbus, Ohio., 1 p.
    Signature cut off.
  - 1856 May 26. Columbus, Ohio., 4 pp.
  - 1856 Sep.2. Columbus, Ohio., 1 p.
  - 1856 Dec.7. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1856 Dec.21. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1857 Jan.1. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1857 Jan.19. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1857 Mar.13. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1857 Apr. 27. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - 1857 Jul. 4. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1857 Aug. 5. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - 1857 Oct. 15. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1857 Nov. 7. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - 1857 Dec. 8. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1858 Jan. 2. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1858 Jan. 30. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1858 Mar .25. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - 1858 Apr.29. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - 1858 Jun. 28. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1858 Jul. 15. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1858 Aug.3. Concord., 3 pp.
  - 1858 Aug. np., 1 p.
  - 1858 Sep.13. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1858 Nov.10. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - 1858 Dec.11. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1859 Feb. 28. Columbus., 2 pp.
    Mutilated.
  - 1859 Mar. 29. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - [1859] May 24. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - [1859] Jun.2. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - [1859] Jul.2. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - [1859] Jul.9. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - [1859] Aug.28. Medina, Ohio., 3 pp.
  - [1859] Oct.7., 4 pp.
    On cars.
  - [1859] Nov.25. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - 1860 Jan.18. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1860 Jan.29. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - 1860 Mar.4. Columbus., 2 pp.
  - 1860 Mar.19. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - 1860 Apr.2. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1860 May 10. Columbus., 3 pp.
  - 1860 Aug.31. Columbus., 1 p.
  - 1860 Sep.23. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - 1860 Nov.7. Columbus., 4 pp.
  - 1861 Apr.7. Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1861 Sep.24. Washington., 1 p.
  - 1862 Feb.19. Washington. 3 pp (LS).
  - 1862 Jun.18. Washington., 4 pp.
  - 1862 Jun.18. Washington. 3 pp (LS).
  - 1863 Sep.23. Washington., 2 pp.
  - [1864] Sep.23. ?, 1 p.
  - [1864] np., 2 pp.
  - 1864 Jan.14. Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1864 Apr.4. Washington. 1 p (LS).
  - 1864 May. np., 1 p.
  - 1864 Jul.20. Newport., 2 pp.
  - 1864 Aug.23. Cherry Hill., 3 pp.
  - 1865 Apr.25. Washington., 1 p.
  - 1865 Jul.8. Wakefield, R.I., 1 p.
  - 1865 Jul.12. Wakefield, R.I., 1 p.
  - 1865 Jul.27. Hanover, N. H., 1 p.
  - 1865 Aug.3. np., 1 p.
  - 1865 Aug.4. Boston., 1 p.
  - 1865 Aug.11. Wakefield., 1 p.
  - 1865 Aug.? 12. Mr. Hooper's., 1 p.
  - 1865 Oct.14. Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1865 Nov.7. Washington., 1 p.
  - 1866 Apr.29. Washington., 2 pp.
  - [1866] May 9. np., 1 p.
  - [1866] Sep.18. Washington., 1 p.
  - 1867 Jan.28. Supreme Court., 1 p.
- Clafin, William. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Apr.12. Boston., (19); 3 pp.
- Cox, Jacob D. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (20)
  - 1895 Apr.18. Cincinnati., 1 p.
  - 1895 Aug.13. Magnolia., 4 pp.
  - 1896 May 20. Cincinnati., 7 pp.
  - 1896 Jun.12. Cincinnati., 4 pp.
  - 1897 Mar. 6. Cincinnati., 3 pp.
- Crapo, William W. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Nov.19. New Bedford., (21); 3 pp.
- Crooks, J. Kirke. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Jan.18. Liverpool., (22); 2 pp.
- Dawes, H. L. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 May 30. Pittsfield, Mass., (23); 2 pp.
- Downing, George T. ALS to: Henry L. Pierce. 1895 Jan.23. Newport., (24); 1 p.
- Eliot, Charles W. TLS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Feb.14. Cambridge., (25); 1 p.
- Forbes, J. M. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Oct.3. np., (26); 2 pp.
- Green, Samuel G. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Jul.4 Interlacken, Switz., (27); 4 pp.
  Grote, H. [Mrs.] ALS to: E. L. Pierce. SEE: Longfellow, Henry W. 1877.
- Hoar, George F. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (28)
  - nd. np [Fragment]., 2 pp.
  - 1895 Mar.11. Worcester., 2 pp.
  - 1895 Jan.3. Worcester., 2 pp.
  - 1895 Aug.5. Worcester. 1 p (TLS).
  - 1896 Apr.18. Washington. 1 p (TLS).
  - 1896 Jun.10. Paris., 4 pp.
  - 1896 Aug.20. Reichenhull., 4 pp.
  - 1896 Dec.18 Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1897 Mar.17. Washington. 1 p (TLS).
- Huntington, F. D. ALS to: [Edward L. Pierce]., (29)
  - 1896 Nov.19 ? Syracuse, N.Y., 4 pp.
  - 1897 Jan.26. Syracuse, N.Y., 4 pp.
- Hutchinson, P.O. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Aug.15. Sidmouth, Eng., (30); 4 pp.
  Also ALS to: E.L.Pierce. from William John Stirling, Aug.15, 1895, 2 pp.
- Jameson, J. Franklin. TLS to: Edward L. Pierce., (31)
  - 1896 Nov.10. Providence, R. I., 1 p.
  - 1896 Nov.14. Providence, R. I., 1 p.
- Johnson, A. B. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (32)
  - 1895 Apr.4. Washington., 1 p.
    Encloses COPY of ALS to: Capt. L.G. Shepard from C. M. Scammon, Mar.11, 1895 --2 pp.
  - 1895 Jun.14. SE Alaska., 4 pp.
- Julian, George Washington, 1817-1899. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Jun.13. Irvington., (33); 3 pp.
  Re: Chase at Free Soil Convention, 1851.
- Langel, G. B. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce 1896 May 8. [Paris]., (34); 4 pp.
- Lecky, W. E. H. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1897 Mar.18. London., (35); 1 p.
- Lodge, Henry Cabot. TLS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1896 Dec.17. Washington., (36); 1 p.
- Long, John D. LS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1897 Jan.30. Boston., (37); 1 p.
- Omitted from series., (38)
- Longfellow, Henry W. ALS to: Mr. Balch. 1874 Sep.29. Cambridge., (39a); 3 pp.
  Re: Biography of Sumner.
- Longfellow, Henry W. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (39b)
  - 1874 Jun.3. Cambridge., 2 pp.
  - 1874 Aug.3. Nahant., 4 pp.
  - 1874 Aug.16. Nahant., 4 pp.
  - 1874 Sep.5. Nahant., 2 pp.
  - 1874 Oct.19. Cambridge., 3 pp.
  - 1874 Nov.2. Cambridge., 4 pp.
  - 1874 Nov.29. Cambridge., 2 pp.
  - 1874 Dec.6. Cambridge., 2 pp.
  - 1876 Nov.4. Cambridge, 3 pp.
  - 1877 Mar.4. Cambridge., 2 pp.
  - 1877 Mar.17. Cambridge., 3 pp.
  - 1877 May 17. Cambridge., 3 pp.
  - 1877 May 17. Cambridge., 1 p.
  - 1877 May 21. Cambridge., 3 pp.
    Encloses ALS to: E.L.Pierce from H. Grote. May 9, 1877, London -3 pp.
  - 1875 Nov.9. Cambridge., 2 pp.
    Enclosing directions for finding Allston's grave, from Miss Judkins.
  - 1876 Feb.14. Cambridge., 4 pp.
  - 1876 Feb.26. Cambridge., 1 p.
  - 1876 Jul.16. Portland., 3 pp.
  - 1876 Oct. 24. Cambridge., 3 pp.
  - 1876 Nov.1. Cambridge., 1 p.
  - 1874 Dec.16. Cambridge., 2 pp.
  - 1874 Dec.20. Cambridge. 1 card.
  - 1874 Dec.29. Cambridge., 1 p.
  - 1875 Feb.16. Cambridge., 3 pp.
    Wrapper enclosed.
  - 1875 Sep.6. Cambridge., 3 pp.
    Encloses ALS to: H.W.Longfellow from J.G.Palfrey, Sep.6, 1875, Cambridge -1 p.
  - 1877 Jun.12. Cambridge., 4 pp.
  - 1877 Jun.15. Cambridge., 2 pp.
  - 1877 Nov.13. Cambridge., 2 pp.
- Murray, James Ormsbee. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (40)
  - 1890 Jul.28. Princeton, N.J., 3 pp.
  - 1896 Jun.3. Princeton, N.J., 4 pp.
  - 1897 Mar.5. Princeton, N.J., 2 pp.
  Palfrey, J. G. ALS to: Henry W. Longfellow. SEE: Longfellow, Henry W. 1875.
- Parker, H.T. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1875 May 11. Kensington Park, London., (41); 2 pp.
- Perkins, J.L. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1875 Nov. 16., (42); 7 pp.
- R, Henry. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1875 May 10. South Kensington., (43); 4 pp.
- Reed, Thomas B. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Aug. 23. Grand Beach., (44); 5 pp.
- Rhodes, James Ford. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (45)
  - 1895 Jul.10. Grasmere, Eng., 8 pp.
  - 1895 Aug.17. Llangollen, N. Wales., 4 pp.
  - ny Oct.27. [Boston]., 2 pp.
- Rice, W. W. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Jan.29. Worcester., (46); 3 pp.
- Richman, Irving B. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Jan.15. St. Gall, Switz., (47); 4 pp.
- Sayler, Samuel M. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (48)
  - 1895 Nov.28. Huntington, Ind., 1 p.
  - 1895 Dec.5. Huntington, Ind., 2 pp.
  Scammon, C. M. TL (COPY) to: Capt. L. G. Shepard. SEE: Johnson, A. B.
- Schurz, Carl. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (49)
  - 1859 Mar.26. Milwaukee., 8 pp.
  - 1859 Apr.6. Milwaukee., 2 pp.
  - 1859 Apr.7. Milwaukee., 2 pp.
  - 1859 Apr.22. New York., 3 pp.
  - 1859 Apr.30. Milwaukee., 4 pp.
  - 1859 May 2. Milwaukee., 2 pp.
  - 1859 May 12. Milwaukee., 4 pp.
  - 1869 Jan.28. St. Louis, Mo., 1 p.
  - 1877 May 4. Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1877 Dec.30. Washington., 2 pp.
  - [1881] Dec.30. Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1887 Mar.18. Washington., 2 pp.
  - 1888 Mar.31. New York., 3 pp.
  - 1888 Apr.4. New York., 3 pp.
  - 1889 Nov.23. New York., 12 pp.
  - 1889 Dec.26. New York., 3 pp.
  - 1891 Jul.10. New York., 2 pp.
  - 1891 Jul.15. New York., 1 p.
  - 1892 Jan.13. New York., 2 pp.
  - 1892 May 24. New York., 3 pp.
  - 1892 Oct.7. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 2 pp.
  - 1892 Nov.28. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 2 pp.
  - 1892 Nov.4. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 3 pp.
  - 1893 Mar.27. New York., 2 pp.
  - 1894 Sep.4. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 3 pp.
  - 1894 Sep.10. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 3 pp.
  - 1894 Dec.17. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 3 pp.
  - 1894 Dec.25. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 3 pp.
  - 1895 Jan.26. Pocantico Hills, N.Y., 2 pp.
  - 1896 Dec.26. New York., 2 pp.
- Sherman, John. TLS to: Edward L. Pierce., (50)
  - 1896 Feb.25. Washington., 1 p.
  Stirling, William John. ALS to: E. L. Pierce. SEE: Hutchinson, P. O.
- Stowe, Harriet Beecher. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1889 Jan.13. Hartford., (51); 1 p.
- Thayer, J. B. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. 1895 Feb.15. Cambridge., (52); 1 p.
- Washburn, John D. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce. ny Aug.6. New York., (53); 3 pp.
- White, Andrew D. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (54)
  - 1895 Sep.26. Ithaca, N.Y., 3 pp.
  - 1896 Jun.5. Washington. 1 p (TLS).
  - 1897 May 6. Ithaca, N.Y. 2 pp (TLS).
- White, Horace. ALS to: Edward L. Pierce., (55)
  - 1896 May 26. New York., 4 pp.
  - 1896 May 30. New York., 2 pp.